Hello Namaskar Jai Hind Vande Mataram.  You are watching
Jio News and we have brought for you
quick big news of selected importance from the country, world and your state and city.  But
before that, if you have not subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe to the channel and turn on the bell notification
and like and
share this video as much as possible.  Today's question for you before looking at the big news.
Which is the smallest continent in the world?  Option A Europe, Option
B Antarctica, Option C Australia and
Option D South America.  Answer this question by
commenting and tell us which state and city
's news do you want to see more?
Tell us by commenting so that we
can show more news of your state or city.  Let us now see
today's quick big news.
Electricity became expensive in UP, fuel
surcharge increased by 10%.  From June, an electricity bill of ₹100 will
now cost ₹110.  People said this is open loot.
Amidst the power crisis in UP,
consumers are now going to be shocked by increased bills.
Because electricity bills are going to become expensive from the month of June.
UP Power
Corporation Limited (UPPCL) has issued an order to impose 10%
Fuel and Power Purchase Adjustment Surcharge (
EPPS).
This simply means that consumers will
now have to pay 10% more electricity bills.
If someone's electricity bill comes to ₹100, he will
now have to pay ₹110.  The Consumer
Council has expressed its displeasure over this and has
demanded an immediate stay on the order.
BSF reached Bengal to install border fencing.  Locals said that now they will be able to sleep peacefully.
Bangladeshis will not be able to harvest our crops.
600 km of West Bengal border.  There is
a part where the
border with Bangladesh is completely open.  There
is no fencing.  And here
recently, when the BSF team arrived to measure the border, the
villagers
distributed sweets.  This area is Sakarpada village
situated on the zero line in Jalngi Bazaar of Murshidabad district.  With a
population of 4000 and 2500
voters, 95% of the people are dependent on agriculture.   The
geography of the village is very sensitive and as soon as the houses
end, fields come and as soon as the fields end,
Bangladesh comes.  The
house of Gram Panchayat member Pintu Mandal is the last one in the village.  The
family owns 30 bighas of
land.   The
government is looking for a safe way on One Nation One Election.  Proposed to be implemented in two phases.
Consideration on holding elections of first 20 states together.  The central government is
looking for a safe path for One Nation One Election and
according to sources associated with the JPC formed for this, the
committee is considering a two-phase transition model
and it will not require holding repeated elections in the states
or drastically reducing the tenure of the assembly.
Instead of bringing the entire country into the electoral cycle simultaneously, the option of two phases
and extending it to 2034 is being
considered the most practical and in the first phase,
assembly elections of about 20 states can be held along with the 2029 Lok Sabha elections.
Banks will remain closed for 11 days in June.
Apart from 11 Sundays and two Saturdays,
banks will remain closed for five days at different places.
See, in the month of June,
banks will remain closed for a total of 11 days in different states of the country
and there will be no work.
According to the calendar released by RBI,
in the month of June, apart from four Sundays and second and fourth
Saturdays, banks will remain closed for five days at different places.
We have made a video regarding bank closure.  You
can go to that video and see more information about
which days and dates the banks will remain closed in your village and city
in the month of June.
Export duty on petrol, diesel and ATF
reduced.  The new rates will come into effect from June 1.   There is
no impact on those buying fuel within the country.  The Central Government has reduced export duty on petrol, diesel and
aviation fuel.
According to a government statement issued, these new rates will come into effect from June 1.
However, there is no change in the existing excise duty rates on petrol and diesel for domestic consumption.  This
means that there will be no
impact on those buying fuel within the country.
According to the government announcement, the new
export duty is as follows.   The
duty on export of petrol has been fixed at ₹1.5 per
litre.  The duty on export of diesel has been
kept at Rs 13.5 per litre.  At the same time, the
duty on export of aviation fuel i.e. ATF has been fixed at ₹9.5 per liter.
Israel captures 900-year-old fort in Lebanon.  The
soldiers hoisted the flag on the hill.
Biggest infiltration in 26 years.
Israeli forces have captured the 900-
year-old Beau Fort fortress and surrounding
hills in southern Lebanon.
Photos
and videos released by Israeli officials showed Israeli flags flying at the fort.
Israeli Defense
Minister Israel Kardes said the army
achieved this success after several days of fierce fighting and air strikes in the surrounding village.  According to Al Jazeera report,
this is Israel's biggest intrusion into Lebanon in the last 26 years.
Vuefort Fort was a major Israeli military base during the Israeli occupation of southern Lebanon from 1982 to 2000,
and is
located on a 700-meter-high hill
overlooking southern Lebanon and a large part of Israel.  Therefore its
military importance is considered very high.
Russia continues to develop anti-aging technology.
Work continues on growing human organs inside pigs.
Anti-aging project worth Rs 2.47 lakh crore.   It
is reported that Russian President Vladimir
Putin has launched
a major government project worth $26 billion, or about $470 billion, to prevent aging and body weakness.
In this program named New Health Preservation Technologies, work will be done on technologies like growing human organs
inside mini pigs i.e. special species of pigs.
According to a report in The Wall Street Journal, the project will focus on technologies such as gene
therapy, lab-grown human organs, and
ultra-low temperature cryotherapy.  The
Russian government claims
that the mission aims to
slow down the aging process and
save the lives of about 17,75,000 people by the end of the decade.
Kerala will now take care of the elderly using the Japanese model.  Buildings will be wheelchair friendly.   Will
connect youth with skill bank.  Kerala, one of the states with the
fastest aging population in the country, has
now prepared to
adopt the Japanese model to deal with this challenge.  The
new state government has
announced the creation of the country's first dedicated department for senior citizens and a Senior Citizens Commission.  According to the Ageing in India
Report 2021, the share of
people above 60 years of age in Kerala was
12.5% ​​in 2011,
which has now increased to 16.5% to 18.7%.
By 2021, the number of elderly people is
expected to reach 20.9% of the total population.
Whereas this will be 13.1% of India
and not only this, by 2051 1/3rd population of the state
is expected to be elderly and
plans are already underway.  But these efforts are
scattered.  Women live longer in Kerala.  That is
why old women are left alone.
Only 24.75% water in 166 ponds of the country.
21.411
billion cubic meters of water flowed in 1 month.
Stock in 15 dams is half of normal.  As summer
reaches its peak, the crisis in the country's ponds has started
deepening.  According to the
latest data released by the Central Water Commission, the
water level in the major ponds of the country has
fallen rapidly from the beginning to the end of May.  The
total live storage in 166 major ponds of the country has come down to 45.419 billion cubic metres till the last week of May.
Which is
only 24.75% of its total capacity.
In the first week of May, these ponds contained
66,830 billion cubic metres of water,
which was 36.41% of their total capacity.
This simply means that within this one month itself,
due to heat and heavy consumption,
about 21.411
billion cubic meters of water has been reduced from the main water sources of the country.
Modi said that the national record of 100 meters was broken thrice in 2 days.  To
beat the heat, keep
drinking local drinks.
Brought a 1000 year old copper plate from the Netherlands.  Prime Minister
Narendra Modi has talked about heat in the Mann Ki Baat program.
PM Modi
said that in our country, the way to fight heat is
often found in the kitchen also.  You might have
also noticed that as the heat increases, the
taste of the kitchen at home changes.
During the programme, the PM
also talked about two famous athletes of the country and PM
Modi said that an event which is being
discussed a lot across the country.  That is the 100 meter
race.  Within just two days, the
national record in the men's 100m race was broken thrice.  The
two athletes who achieved this feat are
Gurinder Veer Singh and Animesh Kujur.  PM
Modi said that you are also familiar with the desi PA.
If you go to North India,
you will find Aamp Panna at many places, giving you the
taste of raw mango and also relief from the heat.  If
you go to Punjab or Haryana, you will get lassi.
In Rajasthan and Gujarat, buttermilk is prepared with every meal.
Sattu Sharbat in Bihar, Jharkhand, Eastern Uttar Pradesh and
what to say about it?  It fills the stomach and
also gives strength.  Kokum Sharbat in Konkan and Goa,
Sthool Kadhi, Panakam Neer Mor and Sambaram in South India
and Bel Panna in Osa are
just not that pair.  It is a part of the tradition of different regions of India.
Allegation by MP Kalyan Banerjee.  BJP
supporters attacked.  Hit him on the head with a stone.
Said the autocratic CM
wants to eliminate his opponents.  TMC MP Kalyan
Banerjee alleged that
he was attacked and injured by BJP supporters outside the police station.
Banerjee had gone to
Chandi Talab police station to submit a memorandum against the arrest of party workers after the assembly elections in Hooghly.
There the crowd surrounded him.
A video of this entire incident
surfaced in which Kalyan Banerjee was
seen raising slogans outside his police station and
later he was seen lying on the ground holding his head.
After some time they
sat outside the police station in protest against this attack.  He was
seen holding a cloth on the back of his head.
However, BJP denied Kalyan's allegations
and said that he was doing drama.
He was not injured and wanted to divert attention from yesterday's
Abhishek Banerjee egg controversy.
Heat reduced in MP, UP and Rajasthan.
Temperatures below 40°C.
Kedarnath Yatra halted for 3 hours due to bad weather.
Sandstorm alert in Bikaner, Jaipur.  It is reported
that due to Western Disturbance, there has been relief from the severe heat that has been going on for the last 15 days in Madhya
Pradesh, Uttar Pradesh, Delhi, Haryana,
Chandigarh, Bihar, Chhattisgarh and Odisha.  Due to
storm, rain and hailstorm, the
mercury has dropped below 40° Celsius in these states.
There is an orange alert for thunderstorms and rain in eight states including Himachal Pradesh,
Uttarakhand, Andhra Pradesh and Rajasthan.
Meanwhile, due to bad weather in Uttarakhand, the
Kedarnath Yatra was halted for 3 hours.
However, the mercury remained above 40° Celsius in 36 cities of the country.
Temperatures in Vidarbha in Maharashtra are still above 44°C
and Chandrapur here was the
hottest city in the country with a temperature of 44.8°C.
Here, a sandstorm hit five districts of Rajasthan,
Sriganganagar, Bikaner, Churu, Hanumangarh and
Sikar at 3:00 pm yesterday
and its impact was felt in about 200 square
km.  Lived in the area of.
General Subramanyam took charge as the new CDS of the country.  He is an
expert on Pakistan-China affairs.  The real task will be to implement the Army's theatre
command model.  It is reported that the
country's new Chief of Defence Staff CDS
General NS Raja Subramanyam has taken charge.
In Delhi, he was given a
guard of honour at the South Block launch.  He
is the third CDS of the country and has
replaced General Anil Chauhan.  General Chauhan
retired on Saturday.  After assuming charge,
he said that the Indian Army,
Navy, Air Force, Defence Ministry and all
related institutions
are united to strengthen the security of the country.  He said that the
updation, procurement and use of indigenous weapons and military equipment in the Indian Army will be
accelerated.
New thinking and new methods will be adopted to increase the strength of the army.
Rahul Gandhi spoke to CBSE students.
Said, those who
questioned the Centre CBSE were called anti-national and terrorists.
Opposition leader in Lok Sabha Rahul
Gandhi has met CBSE class 12 students.
He posted a video
of his conversation with students on social media platform experts
and targeted the
central government over the irregularities in on-screen marking OSM.
In the video, Rahul
Gandhi asked the students about their problems.
He said that the students had
asked only a few simple questions to CBSE and the Modi government but instead of answers they were
insulted.  They were
given names like anti-national spy and terrorist.
Vedant was also among the students Rahul spoke to.
A post by Vedant went viral
in which he said that the
scanned copies uploaded on the portal during re-evaluation were
not his.
After Vedanta, many other students also made similar complaints.
Five people were arrested in the attack on TMC MP Abhishek Banerjee.  Mamata Banerjee said that if she had
not worn a helmet, she would have lost her life.  BJP
leaders and officers put pressure for discharge.
Police have arrested five accused in the attack on TMC MP Abhishek Banerjee in West Bengal.
The
arrests were made after an overnight raid based on video footage.
Mamata Banerjee
termed the attack a conspiracy and said that if
Abhishek had not worn a helmet, he could have lost his
life.  He alleged that
BJP leaders and
police put pressure to get Abhishek, who was admitted in the hospital, discharged soon.  Abhishek was
attacked in South Sonarpur on Saturday.  Where he
went to meet the workers who were victims of post-election violence.  Today's good thought: If the
world ran on trust, no door would be
locked.  Do let us know how you liked this video
in the comment section.  If you like the video then please
like and share the video and to
watch such [Music] interesting videos
subscribe to our channel Jio News
and press the bell icon and do check
our
playlist and community tab [Music] to watch our old and latest videos.
So see you in the next video.
Thank you for now.